<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mike C.C. Shih</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mike C.C. Shih</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 05:13:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 05:13:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>My publications are listed on my Google Scholar profile. My coding profile is on GitHub.
I co-authored Chapter 3 of the book Methods in Extracellular Matrix Biology, entitled &amp;ldquo;Nonlinear optical imaging of extracellular matrix proteins&amp;rdquo;. I appreciate the chance and efforts James Fitzpatrick and Robert Mecham offered.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 05:13:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>DL Segmentation on FIB-SEM Datasets GitHub: DL Segmentation on FIB-SEM Datasets
Features: Python, Keras, TensorFlow
This repository holds code for deep-learning-based image segmentation. The target datasets were 3D cellular images acquired from a Focused Ion Beam Scanning Electron Microscope (FIB-SEM). The goal is to label cells and their subcellular structures, such as nucleus, mitochondria, etc. These labels can offer medical insights by analyzing their features under different genetic conditions and treatments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects_backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 05:13:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects_backup/</guid>
      <description>DL Segmentation on FIB-SEM Datasets GitHub: DL Segmentation on FIB-SEM Datasets
Features: Python, Keras, TensorFlow
This repository holds code for deep-learning-based image segmentation. The target datasets were 3D cellular images acquired from a Focused Ion Beam Scanning Electron Microscope (FIB-SEM). The goal is to label cells and their subcellular structures, such as nucleus, mitochondria, etc. These labels can offer medical insights by analyzing their features under different genetic conditions and treatments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ripley&#39;s K Demo: 02 K test</title>
      <link>/posts/ktest_demo_02_ktest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ktest_demo_02_ktest/</guid>
      <description>Use previously generated point process for Ripley&amp;rsquo;s K test The default size of point process generator is 20 x 20 Please visit the code on my GitHub  # denpendency  import os, sys import scipy.stats import pandas as pd import numpy as np import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import matplotlib.style import matplotlib as mpl import spatialstat.ppsim as ppsim import spatialstat.spatialpattern as spatialpattern %load_ext autoreload %autoreload 2 # define IO dir path = &amp;#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ripley&#39;s K Demo: 01 Point Process Simulation</title>
      <link>/posts/ktest_demo_01_simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ktest_demo_01_simulator/</guid>
      <description>Before demonstrating Ripley&amp;rsquo;s K function ($K(t)$), $L(t)$, and $H(t)$), I have to first simulate two types of point process: 1. Poisson point process and 2. Thomas point process. The point process generator is adpated from Connor Johnson&amp;rsquo;s blog post. The default size of point process generator is 20 x 20 Please visit the code on my GitHub  # denpendency  import os, sys import scipy.stats import pandas as pd import numpy as np import matplotlib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Point Pattern Analysis</title>
      <link>/posts/point_pattern_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 14:44:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/point_pattern_analysis/</guid>
      <description>As super-resolution microscopies get popular, we are seeing increasing researchers use them to resolve the spatial distribution of organelles. One good example is Airyscan. The resolution of Airyscan is slightly lower than SIM, yet, its success rate and stability make it the best bet when it comes to imaging organelle markers (MitoTracker or LysoTracker).
Once image acquisition and labeling are made, to conclude, a certain level of spatial analysis could be necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi I am Mike C.C. Shih, an image data scientist at Washington University in St. Louis. Demonstrated experience in multi-dimensional imaging/analysis and numerical modeling (6+ years). Strong proficiency in image processing, machine learning, and deep learning model development. Passionate about leveraging the usage of image data science and imaging strategies to offer insights into biomedical and biological R&amp;amp;D.
Languages: Python, R, MATLAB, Unix shell, SQL
Tools: Numpy, Pandas, TensorFlow, Matplotlib, SciKit-Image, SciKit-Learn, OpenCV, Git</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>